Daniel Cox

1665 Logan St. Apt. #648 • Denver, CO 80203 (916) 251-6606 Mobile

dcox0039@gmail.com

Dynamic, young business professional with internship and full time experiences in mortgage analysis, product marketing, financial analysis, and business/organizational management. I've been able to learn and use my experiences to create tangible solutions to improve revenue and profitability.

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

- Financial Analysis
- Risk Management
- Forecasting
- Operations Accounting Principles
- Risk Management
- Statistical Modeling
- Client Relationship Management
- Business Development
- Culture Change
- Inventory Tracking
- Microsoft Office Applications

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Spider Staging, A Division of SafeWorks LLC; Seattle WA/Denver, CO January 2015 – Present

Spider Staging is the market share and revenue leader in the suspended access (Swing stage) industry. SafeWorks is a \$89MM company with an estimated \$50MM of revenue coming from the Spider Staging brand. Spider Staging delivers suspended access solutions globally and is the only manufacturer of traction and drum hoists in the U.S.

Sales and Operations Trainee

- Learning through a rotational training program the fundamentals of how to manage budgets with the
 use of forecasting and historic data, profit and loss statement analysis, financial statement analysis to
 qualify customers, and general accounting practices for an autonomously operating branch of a
 suspended access company
- Helped correct a 23.6% inventory variance resulting in an estimated \$226,000 increase in potential revenue
- Building suspended access solutions for \$10MM+ construction and restoration projects
- Applying continuous improvement and lean operations principles to decrease inventory and processing costs, increasing net margins and profitability
- Evaluating potential clients with the use of primary and secondary research regarding financial stability and operating revenue

The Mansion of Iowa; Des Moines, IA

May 2014 - August 2014

The Mansion of Iowa is a small interior design firm, specializing in high-end designs, furniture, and art. The organization has expanded twice within the last ten years with the newest location opening in 2014 in the Phoenix, Arizona area.

Business Model and Operations Analyst Intern

- Used secondary and primary market research to modify product offering to reach emerging millennial markets, a previously untapped market segment
- Used historical data to forecast demand, costs, and market size which allowed for a 7% increase in net profit
- Decreased inventory cost by 13% in two months using just in time inventory principles and pricing models based on forecasted demand
- Took part in negotiations regarding a potential buyout, ultimately resulting in no sale of the business

Bruno Events Team/PGA Tour - Principal Charity Classic; Des Moines, IA March 2013 - July 2013

Based out of Birmingham, Alabama, Bruno Events Team is contracted to plan, manage, and execute major events. Bruno Events Team specializes in sporting related events with \$10MM+ sponsor profiles. Major clients include the Professional Golf Association, and University of Alabama football program.

Marketing and Sales Intern

- Built and managed sponsor databases, including collections and account management for a \$12 million sponsorship profile which included Wells Fargo & CO, Principal Financial Group, BNY Mellon, and J.P. Morgan Chase, amongst others
- Provided sales support by prospecting and calling on potential sponsors
- Designed golf tournament media guide and provided a marketing consulting function by consulting with sponsors regarding their business strategy to best determine advertisement placement
- Updated and managed media content including: websites, mobile application content, and on course communications

Iowa Barnstormers – Arena Football League; Des Moines, IA January 2013 – August 2013

The Iowa Barnstormers are one eight AFL teams, having the third highest attendance in the AFL during the 2013 season.

Marketing and Game Day Operations Intern

- Used internal historical data to plan and execute advertising expenditures while measuring effectiveness with the usage of promotional objectives
- Increased game day ticket revenue by 8% from previous season
- Implemented a new marketing strategy, which turned a 13% operating loss into a 6% operating profit, by better engaging their intended target market
- Planned and executed marketing operations including signage placement, social media engagement, sponsor relationship management, and hospitality suite coordination

Wells Fargo & Company

June 2012 – August 2012

Wells Fargo & CO is the third largest bank in the U.S. with \$1,532,784MM in assets worldwide.

Correspondent Lending Intern

- Created the current Wells Fargo Home Mortgage department-wide career development program
 including the Career Roadmap for team member development and the corresponding Manager's
 Manual for management to engage employees for the purposes of identifying and developing
 potential managers
- Performed risk analysis and credit analysis for prospective banks and their secondary mortgage bundles with the use of historical and statistical modeling
- Learned how interest rates affect balance sheet activity as it relates to the majors banks and the secondary mortgage market
- Helped reach a market share of 53% by demanding stronger credit profiles for lender's mortgage bundles

Education

Drake University - Des Moines, IA

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration – Marketing and Management

Athletics

- NCAA Athlete (Football)
- Drake University Athletics' 2012 *Committed to Excellence Award* winner, given for academic achievement, community service, and athletic performance
- Pioneer Football League Honor Roll

Service, Scholarships, and Accomplishments

- Completed over 400 hours of community service in four years
- Summited Mount Kilimanjaro in Tanzania, Africa
- Completed two week community service trip to Tanzania, Africa
- Presidential Scholarship Recipient